the39clues.com 2018-11-26

# Privacy Policy | Scholastic Inc.

Scholastic knows that your privacy is important to you, and we want you to know that it is important to us too. Unless otherwise specified in connection with a particular activity, this Policy explains the types of information we collect through our Web sites, online services or applications on which this Policy is posted (each, a "Site"), how we will use, disclose and protect this information once it is collected, and how you can opt out of some of our uses and disclosures of your information. By visiting our Site, as permitted by law, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Here are a few general things to keep in mind as you read this Policy:

  * Our Scholastic Education Technology Products Privacy Policy, not this Privacy Policy, applies to our collection and use of data collected from schools, teachers, parents and students through our educational software products.

  * The Site is owned and operated by Scholastic Inc. or one or more of its corporate affiliates (referred to collectively in this policy as "we," "us," "our" and other similar pronouns).

  * Our Kids Privacy Policy applies to Sites or areas of our Sites that are directed to kids under age 13 (our "Kids Sites").

  * **As permitted by law and except when we tell you otherwise in connection with a particular activity, we may share your Personal Information with third parties for third party marketing purposes. You can ask us not to by sending us your name, email and phone number to: Opt-Out Request, Scholastic Inc., 557 Broadway, New York, NY 10012. For further information, see theOpt In and Opt Out section below.**

  * This Policy may be supplemented from time to time by other terms that are posted on and apply to specific Web sites or features, online services or applications. In addition, as our business changes, this Policy may also change, so we encourage you to come back to this page from time to time.

  * This Policy _does not_ apply to information that we collect from or about you other than through our Site, such as over the phone, by mail, or in person. Your right to opt out of our use and sharing of your Personal Information with third parties for their own marketing purposes, however, also applies to the Personal Information that we collect offline.

  * **This Site places cookies and local shared objects on your computer or device which are further described below. As permitted by law, by using the Site, you agree to this.**

  * **If you are located outside of the United States, you should know that the information you provide to us is being transmitted to us and processed in the United States and in other countries by us or our service providers on our behalf, and will be protected subject to this Privacy Policy and applicable laws, which may not be as protective as the laws in your country. As permitted by law, by using the Site, you agree to this.**

  * **Advertisements shown to you on this Site and elsewhere may be customized to your interests and preferences based on your Personal Information and Web site usage information collected through our Site, unless you opt out. Opt-out instructions can be found at:<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/> and <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>. (You have to opt out separately for each of your devices, and for each Web browser you use, such as Internet Explorer, Firefox or Safari.) Even if you opt out, we may still suggest offerings to you on our Site based on your history at our Site.**

### Opt In and Opt Out

You may have the right to opt in to or opt out of certain of our uses and disclosures of your Personal Information. For example, we may ask you if you want to get marketing messages from us when you submit Personal Information to us on the Site. If you do get marketing emails from us, you can tell us you don't want to get them by clicking on the opt-out link in those emails.

Or, contact us through this [form](http://scholastic.custhelp.com/app/ask/p/82/incidents.subject/Third%20Party%20Opt%20Out%20Request) or write to us at: **Opt-Out Request, Scholastic Inc., 557 Broadway, New York, NY 10012**. Please include your name, address, email and phone number and tell us if you want us to stop sharing your Personal Information with third parties for marketing purposes, or if you want us to stop sending a particular kind of communication. If you are writing about a communication sent to you by Scholastic, please include the name or type of the communication and, if applicable, the name of the specific Scholastic entity or business.

It may take us a few days to process any opt-out request. In addition, if you opt out of having your Personal Information shared with third parties for marketing purposes, you may continue to receive communications from third parties who received your Personal Information from us before we processed your opt-out. To stop receiving such communications, please contact the third party directly.

**What information is collected on this Site?**

**_User-Provided Information_**  
"Personal Information" is information that can be used to identify an individual or allow someone to contact an individual. We may collect Personal Information such as:

  * name
  * postal or physical address
  * email address
  * telephone number
  * photographs, videos or audio recordings
  * credit card and other payment information
  * certain school/education information

Personal Information may also include information, such as names and email addresses, that we collect from you about other people when you share content on our Site with someone else, purchase a gift, or create a teacher account for a classroom.

We may also collect information such as your date of birth and certain demographic information. We do not generally treat these as Personal Information except when tied to information such as that listed above or as required by law.

In some cases, information about you or your device, including the information detailed above, may be collected on our Site directly by a third party, and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. For example, widgets or other third party tools may be used on our Site to provide services like content sharing, new feeds, comment-filtering, or blog hosting, and our applications may be used through third party platforms. See Social Networking below for more information about how we may use third party social networks.

**_Site Usage Information_**  
When you visit our Site, our servers automatically collect the Internet protocol, or "IP", address associated with your computer, to help us track and resolve issues with Site functionality or administration. An IP address is a string of numbers that is usually controlled by a user's Internet service provider, and automatically assigned when a user's computer connects to the Internet. In some cases, we may get general geographic location information from your IP address.

We may also capture "clickstream data" about your Site usage. Clickstream data includes information about your "clicks" or actions on our Sites, such as what you see or click on during your visit and how you interacted with certain features. It can include information about your computer or device, Web browser and operating system and settings and may include referrer URL information that is automatically passed to us (that is, information about where the user came from before arriving on our Site, which may include search terms in the URL string).

To track information about use of our Sites, we use various technological tools. For example:

  * Cookies are small data files sent by a Web site or application and stored on your computer or device at the request of that site or app. A cookie stores information related to your browser to enable us to recognize your browser on return visits to our Site and remember your preferences. Most browsers can be set to detect browser cookies and to let you reject them, but refusing cookies may make it difficult to use the Site. To learn more about browser cookies, including how to manage or delete them, look in the Tools, Help or similar section of your Web browser, or visit [http://allaboutcookies.org](http://allaboutcookies.org/).

  * Local shared objects, such as "Flash cookies," may be stored on your computer or device through a media player or other software installed on your computer or device. Local shared objects operate a lot like cookies, but cannot be managed in the same way. Depending on how local shared objects are enabled on your computer or device, you may be able to manage them using software settings. For information on managing Flash cookies, visit <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>.

  * A pixel tag (also known as a "clear GIF" or "web beacon") is a tiny image - typically just one-pixel - that can be placed on a Web page or in an email to you, to tell us when you have displayed that page or opened that email.

These technologies allow us to assign a unique customer number to you.

We use third party service providers to assist us in collecting and understanding Site usage information.

As permitted by law, by using our Site, you agree to our use of these tracking technologies.

Some of our mobile applications may collect information about the location of your mobile device so we can provide location-based services. To manage location services, check the settings on your mobile device or contact your mobile service provider or device manufacturer. Specific mobile applications may include additional terms that relate only to those apps.

**How is your information used?**  
We may use the information we collect from and about you to perform various business functions including, for example:

  * authenticating you as a user and enabling you to use the
  * processing and fulfilling transactions
  * maintaining and administering the Site and your account with us
  * responding to your requests
  * analyzing the Site, making overall Site improvements and developing new features
  * sending you marketing and other communications, including information about products, services, and events, of ours and of others, that we think might interest you
  * protecting our rights and property and the rights, property, and safety of others
  * investigating suspected fraud or other unlawful activity
  * personalizing or customizing our Site to your interests and history with us (for example, remembering items in your shopping cart)
  * evaluating email marketing and other campaigns
  * tailoring ads displayed to you on our Site and elsewhere to your interests and history with us
  * other purposes disclosed when Personal Information is submitted to us
  * where otherwise permitted or required by applicable law

To do these things, we may match information collected from you in different ways or at different times, including both Personal Information and Site usage information, and use that information along with information obtained from other sources (including third parties) such as demographic information and updated contact information.

**Social Networking**  
We use several social networking platforms, such as Facebook, to communicate with our customers. If we display or link to this Privacy Policy on such third party platforms, then this Policy applies to our use of Personal Information and other information you submit to us there, but it does not apply to what those platforms do with your information.

Some tools on our Site allow you to share content from our Site through a third party social network. If you use these tools, please be aware that third party social networking services have their own privacy policies, and we encourage you to read them.

You may also be able to give us information on our Site that you have already provided to a third party social network. For example, you may be able to log-in to our Site using your Facebook account information. By doing so, you consent to our collection and use of any Personal Information or other data we receive from that third party in accordance with this Policy.

**Do we share Personal Information and Site Usage Information with others?**  
Yes. We share the information we collect on the Site with others who need it to provide services and so we can operate or support the Site or our business.

Information sharing also happens when it is a necessary part of certain Site features, such as when you post your information to public areas on the Site where other Site users can see it.

We may also share your Personal Information:

  * with our affiliates and third parties for their marketing and other purposes, unless you tell us not to by following the instructions in the Opt In and Opt Out section above

  * with our co-sponsor(s) if we obtain your Personal Information in connection with a contest, sweepstakes, offering, or other promotional activity that is jointly offered by us and any third party(ies)

  * if you are a registered teacher through us, we may make your name, school name and school location available in an online lookup tool for parents and others, unless you opt out by contacting us using the email address or telephone number available under Contact Us below (in some cases, your opt-out may not be effective until the next school year)

  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or property or that of others, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud or respond to a government, judicial or other legal request, or to comply with the law

  * in connection with a corporate change or dissolution, including for example a merger, acquisition, reorganization, consolidation, bankruptcy, liquidation, sale of assets or wind down of business; and due diligence related to the foregoing

  * in additional circumstances subject to your consent

In addition, we may share Site usage information (including aggregate data) with others, for their own use, in a form that does not include your name or contact information.

**Third-Party Tracking, Ad Servers and Networks**  
Third parties, such as ad networks, web analytics companies and social networking platforms, may collect personally identifiable information about your online activities over time and across our Sites and other third party online properties or services. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites, and general geographic information derived from your IP address, in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. These advertisements may appear on this Site and on other Web sites. These companies may employ cookies, clear GIFs and other tracking technologies to cause relevant ads to be displayed to you. Some advertisements may display icons that consumers can click on for more information about their advertising choices.

For information about the privacy practices of third party advertising companies who serve ads on our Site, visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/> and <http://www.operative.com/privacy-policy/>. **For more information about third-party advertisers and how to prevent them from using your information, visit the NAI's consumer Web site at[http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) or <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>.** Our Sites do not honor "do not track" signals transmitted by users' web browsers, so we encourage you to visit these links if you would like to opt out of certain tracking. If you do want to opt out using these tools, you need to opt out separately for each of your devices and for each Web browser you use (like Internet Explorer, Firefox or Safari) on each device. For mobile applications, please visit your device settings or third party ad blocking tools. 

**Your Access Rights**  
You may review or change certain Personal Information in your user account on the Site (if you have one) by logging in to the "My Account" or similar area of the Site or by contacting us using the Contact Us information below. You may also contact us as detailed below to exercise other rights under applicable law, including the right to access, review, correct, obtain a copy, port, delete, or block or withdraw consent to the processing of certain Personal Information (without affecting the lawfulness of processing based on consent before its withdrawal). We may ask you to verify your identity before we provide you with your information or make changes to it. We reserve the right to keep certain Personal Information necessary for record-keeping to the extent permitted and/or required by law, including any statutory retention requirements.

If you are a parent, guardian or teacher and you or your minor child or student have provided us with Personal Information about that child or student, you may:

  * revoke any consent you may have provided for that child
  * review or revise that Personal Information
  * ask us to delete the child's Personal Information
  * ask us not to collect Personal Information from the child in the future
  * exercise any other rights detailed above to that child's Personal 

Information

by contacting us at:

Parent/Teacher Request for Information  
Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  

We may require verification of your identity and relationship to the child. If your child or student is under the age of 13, please see our Kids Privacy Policy for additional information.

**Security**  
While we have policies and procedures in place and take reasonable measures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of Personal Information collected on this Site (like SSL encryption for transmissions of payment card information), we cannot guarantee that information will be absolutely safe from intrusion during transmission, while stored on our systems, or when otherwise in our care. Except as expressly required by applicable statute or regulation, we will have no liability for disclosure of your Personal Information due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties during or after transmission.

If you create an account on our Site, you are responsible for maintaining the strict confidentiality of your account password, and for any activity that occurs under your account credentials, whether or not authorized by you. Please notify us of any unauthorized use of your account or any other breach of security.

If we believe that the security of your Personal Information in our care may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development, as soon as possible under the circumstances. If we have your email address, we may notify you by email. **Where permitted by law, you consent to our use of email as a means of such notification. If you want to be notified by U.S. mail instead, please email us at securitycs@scholastic.com.**

**"Linked-To" Web Sites**  
This Site may contain links, banners or advertisements that lead to other third party Web sites or use third party services. We are not responsible for these other sites and services, and their privacy policies (not this Policy) will govern the collection and use of your information there. We encourage you to read them.

**Internet Safety**  
We encourage parents and teachers to talk with their children and students about how to be safe online. Here are some resources to help you do that.

  * Ways to Take Charge of the Web  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/article/ten-ways-takecharge-web](http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/article/ten-ways-takecharge-web)
  * Internet Safety Commandments  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2012/05/internet-safety-commandments-summer](http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2012/05/internet-safety-commandments-summer)
  * Keeping Kids Safe Online  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/parents/resources/article/your-child-technology/keeping-kids-safe-online](http://www.scholastic.com/parents/resources/article/your-child-technology/keeping-kids-safe-online)
  * <http://www.commonsensemedia.org/>
  * <http://www.ikeepsafe.org/>

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**  
We may change this Policy from time to time. When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed Policy on this page with a new "Last Updated" date. We may choose (or be required by law) to tell you about changes by additional means, such as by sending an email to the email address we have on file for you. In some cases, we will request your consent to the changes.

**  
Other Issues**

_What is our legal basis of processing?_

Some jurisdictions require an explanation of the legal basis for the collection and processing of Personal Information. We have several different legal grounds on which we collect and process Personal Information, including: (1) as necessary to perform a transaction (such as when we respond to your requests); (2) as necessary to comply with a legal obligation (such as when we use Personal Information for record keeping to satisfy legal and compliance obligations); (3) consent (where you have provided consent as appropriate under applicable law, such as for marketing); and (4) necessary for legitimate interests (such as when we act to maintain our business generally). With respect to legitimate interests, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of you which require protection of Personal Information, such legitimate interests are the fulfilment of the processing purposes described in this Privacy Policy that are not necessary for the performance of a contract or for our compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject. 

_How long do we retain your Personal Information?_

We typically retain Personal Information related to marketing activities for as long as you accept marketing communications from us, and upon request, we will securely delete such data in accordance with applicable law. For Personal Information that we collect and process for other purposes, as described above, we typically retain such Personal Information for no longer than the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, and as otherwise needed to address tax, corporate, compliance, education law, litigation, and other legal rights and obligations. 

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions or comments regarding our privacy practices, you may contact us at:

Parent/Teacher Request for Information  
Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
U.S.A.  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 1-800-SCHOLASTIC  

This Privacy Policy replaces our former privacy policy which you can find posted here.

**Effective Date:** May 25, 2018

**Scholastic Kids (Under 13) Privacy Policy**

This Kids Privacy Policy applies to information we collect from users of our Sites, online services or applications directed to children who are under the age of 13 (our "Kid Sites"). When we use the word "kid" or "child" in this Policy, we mean a user under the age of 13. When we use the word "parent" in this Policy, we mean a kid's parent or legal guardian. The operators of our Kids Sites are listed here. Each Kids Site's operator is referred to in this Kids Privacy Policy as "we," "us," "our" or other similar pronouns. Some of our Kids Sites may have additional privacy policies, terms of use, site descriptions or Frequently Asked Questions that add to this Kids Privacy Policy by giving more details about what kids can do there, and how we use Personal Information collected there. 

### _WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED FROM KID USERS THROUGH THE KIDS SITES?_

By law, our Kids Sites cannot condition a child's participation in an online activity on the child's providing more information than is reasonably necessary. If we do collect personal information from a child online, the law allows us to keep that information only as long as is reasonably necessary to fulfill the purpose for which the information is collected.

**_Direct Collection_**  
We may collect the following Personal Information from our child visitors under the age of 13:

  * email address
  * parent email address or other online contact information
  * photo or other image or recording
  * school name/location
  * teacher email address or other contact information

We may also collect information from child visitors such as first name, last initial, general geo-location information (but no more specific than city or zip code), age or grade, gender or hobbies, activities, likes/dislikes (such as most recent book read, favorite book genre), which we consider Personal Information only if combined with any of the other items of Personal Information listed above. We may also collect date of birth (for age-screening purposes only), but we do not keep date of birth unless we specifically say we do in connection with a particular activity.

Some of the most common activities on our Kids Sites that collect Personal Information are newsletters, sweepstakes and contests, and e-cards. These activities require an email address to participate. For more information about these features, see Newsletters, Sweepstakes and Contests on Kids Sites and e-Cards on Kids Sites.

When we collect Personal Information from a child, we ask the child's parent for consent before we collect it, except as permitted by law, such as where we are only using an email address to respond directly to a request from the child. If the email is collected for a one-time response, we delete it after the response is sent. If the email is collected to respond more than once to the child, we will also ask for the parent's email, so we can let the parent know that the child has given us Personal Information and give the parent a chance to tell us to delete that Personal Information before we re-contact the child. In that case, we delete the child's email either at the parent's request, or, if no such request is made, when we have finished responding to the child and otherwise fulfilled the purpose for which the email was collected (see, for example, Newsletters, Sweepstakes and Contests on Kids Sites below).

We may request the parent's consent in any way the law allows. For example, if the child's Personal Information will be used only by us, we may ask for the parent's consent by email. If the child's Personal Information will be disclosed on the Site or shared with a third party, we may verify that the person providing consent is the parent by asking for consent in connection with a credit card transaction. Parents have the option to consent to the collection and use of their children's information without consenting to the disclosure of that information to third parties, except to the extent that disclosure of such information is a necessary part of the activity for which parental consent is given. Notice of the information collection, use and disclosure practices associated with a particular online activity will be provided to the parent when we ask for consent. That notice will also be on the Kids Site to which it applies. Sometimes, in connection with the direct notice to the parent, we may collect the parent or child's name from the child (for example, the child's first name, so that the parent knows which of their children wants to sign up for an activity).

On our Kids Sites where the main audience is not children under 13, we may ask for (but do not save) a user's date of birth to determine whether parental consent is required for a child to use a particular feature, or whether it's appropriate for a child to use a particular feature.

There are many activities on our Kids Sites that kids can participate in without having to share any Personal Information. Examples are: games; moderated and pre-screened online writing features and message boards; basic kid account registration.

**_Passive Collection_**  
When a child visits a Kids Site, our systems automatically collect the Internet protocol, or "IP", address associated with the child's computer. An IP address is a string of numbers that is usually controlled by a user's Internet service provider, and automatically assigned when a user's computer connects to the Internet. We use this information to identify and fix problems with the way our Kids Sites work. IP addresses can also give us general location information from our child users, such as continent or region within the United States.

We also collect "clickstream data". Clickstream data is information about a user's "clicks" or actions on a Kids Site, such as the pages, content or ads seen or clicked on, downloads, games played, and other activity. Clickstream data also includes information about a child's computer or device, Web browser and operating system and settings and may include referrer URL information that is automatically passed to us (that is, information about where the user came from before arriving on our Site, which may include search terms in the URL string).

Here are examples of the technical tools we use to collect usage information about children's visits to our Kids Sites:

  * _Cookies_ : Cookies are small data files sent by a Web site or application and saved on a user's computer or device at the request of that site or app. A browser cookie stores information about the user's Web browser, so we can recognize that browser when a user comes back to that site or app. Cookies can help us save a user's preferences on a Kids Site, and can also be used to help with age-screening tools. Most browsers can be set to detect or reject browser cookies, but refusing cookies may, in some cases, make it difficult or impossible to use a Kids Site. More information about the use of browser cookies, including how to manage or delete them, is available in the tools, help or similar section of Web browsers and at [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). **Where permitted by law, by allowing their children to use our Kids Sites, parents agree to the placement of cookies on their child's computer or device.**

  * _Local shared object_ : Local shared objects, such as "Flash cookies," may be stored on a computer or device through a media player or other software installed on that computer or device. Local shared objects operate a lot like cookies, but cannot be managed in the same way. Flash cookies are often used in activities like games, to store scores or other progress. Depending on how local shared objects are enabled on a computer or device, they can be managed using software settings. Information about managing Flash cookies is available at <http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-local-shared-objects-flash.html>. As with browser cookies, some features of our Kids Sites will not work as well if Flash cookies are turned off. **Where permitted by law, by allowing their children to use our Kids Sites, parents agree to the placement of local shared objects on their child's computer or device.**

  * _Pixel tags_ : A pixel tag (also known as a "clear GIF" or "web beacon") is a tiny image that can be placed on a Web page or in emails to users, to tell us when a user has displayed that page or opened those emails.

We use tracking tools to give our users a better experience - for example, so users don't have to log in every time they return to our Kids Sites, or so we can show our users content we think they will like. We also use these tools to learn how we can make our Kids Sites better. For example, by counting the number of users who visit our Sites, particular pages or activities, or checking to see if users open our emails, we can figure out how effective our content is.

These tools may allow us to assign a unique number to our child users, but this number cannot be used to track child users across different, unaffiliated Web sites. We also do not link a child's user number or Kids Site usage information with the child's Personal Information, or collect geolocation information more specific than city or zip code, unless we get consent from the child's parent. We do not track kids across different, unaffiliated sites, online services or applications using any other persistent identifiers unless we have a parent's consent. We do not use IP addresses or the child's unique number to attempt to identify individual kid users except under the circumstances described in the "Legal Disclosures" paragraph of this Kids Privacy Policy.

**Third-Party Ad Servers and Networks**  
We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our Kids Sites. For information about their privacy practices, visit <http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/> and <http://www.operative.com/privacy-policy/>. However, we use these services in a manner that complies with this Kids Privacy Policy. For mobile applications, please visit your child's device settings or third party ad blocking tools. 

### _HOW IS THE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT KID USERS USED AND SHARED?_

**Use of Information**  
The Personal Information we collect from or about a child via our Kids Sites is used to provide services and features (e.g., contests, e-cards, sweepstakes, e-books and e-readers), process and respond to the child's requests (e.g., newsletter or other email sign-ups), send password reminders, provide customer service, and to contact the child or the child's parent about the child's use of the Kids Site.

**Community Features**  
Kids can post messages on some of our Kids Sites (for example, on message boards), and share ideas, creations and comments (for example, through blog commenting tools or online writing features), but these postings are moderated before they are made public. We take reasonable measures to delete Personal Information included in these submissions before they are posted.

**Disclosure to Service Providers**  
The Personal Information and site usage information we collect on Kids Sites may be collected or accessed by our service providers (whether third parties or our corporate affiliates) who support and administer the internal operations of our Kids Sites, such as to enable registration and maintenance of accounts, to fulfill account requests, and to provide customer service. Our service providers who have access to children's Personal Information can use that Personal Information only to do the tasks we engage them to do; they cannot use it for any other reason or for their own purposes, and we require them to agree to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of that Personal Information. Service providers also assist us in collecting and understanding Kids Site usage information. We may share non-personally identifiable Kids Site usage information (including aggregate data) with others, for their own use.

**Legal Disclosures**  
We reserve the right to release a child's Personal Information, or to use a child's IP address or unique number to attempt to identify a child user, to the extent consistent with applicable law, when we believe release is required to comply with federal, state or local law (such as cooperating with a judicial process or law enforcement investigation), to maintain the safety and integrity of the Kids Site or Site, to enforce any applicable terms of use, or to protect the child or our or others' rights, property or safety, or to take precautions against any other liability.

**Business Transfers**  
In connection with a corporate change or dissolution, including for example a merger, acquisition, reorganization, consolidation, bankruptcy, liquidation, sale of assets, wind-down of business or related due diligence, children's Personal Information and children's site usage Information may be among the transferred assets or disclosed to third parties. To the extent required by law, we will get parental consent before sharing children's Personal Information under such circumstances, and will obtain the agreement of the third party to maintain the confidentiality, security and integrity of that Personal Information.

**Other Disclosures**  
Unless we have obtained a child's parent's consent as required by applicable law, a child's Personal Information is not shared with third parties (even with corporate affiliates, unless they are co-operators of the Kids Site where the Personal Information was collected) for their own use or disclosure except as described under the "Legal Disclosures" and "Business Transfers" paragraphs of this Kids Privacy Policy. 

**_SECURITY_**  
While we have policies and procedures in place and take reasonable measures to protect the confidentiality, security and integrity of Personal Information collected on our Kids Sites, we cannot guarantee that information will be absolutely safe from intrusion during transmission, while stored on our systems, or when otherwise in our care. Except as expressly required by applicable statute or regulation, we will have no liability for disclosure of information due to errors or unauthorized acts of third parties during or after transmission.

If we believe that the security of Personal Information in our care may have been compromised, we may seek to notify users of that development, as soon as possible under the circumstances. If we have a parent or teacher email address associated with a child user whose Personal Information may have been compromised, we may send the notice by email. **Users who prefer to get such a notice by U.S. mail should email us at securitycs@scholastic.com.**

**_INFORMATION FOR EDUCATORS_**  
Under the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA), schools may (but are not required to) act as intermediaries for parents, by giving permission for students under 13 to provide Personal Information in connection with certain online school activities, subject to any applicable school or school district policies.

**_HOW CAN YOU REVIEW YOUR CHILD'S PERSONAL INFORMATION, DEACTIVATE YOUR CHILD'S KIDS SITE ACCOUNT OR DELETE YOUR CHILD'S PERSONAL INFORMATION?_**  
If you are a parent of one of our child users, you can

  * review your child's Personal Information
  * ask us to deactivate your child's Kids Site account
  * revoke any consent you have given for your child
  * ask us to delete Personal Information your child has given us
  * ask that we no longer collect Personal Information from your child
  * exercise any other rights to your child's Personal Information, including the right to access, review, correct, obtain a copy, port, delete, or block or withdraw consent to the processing of certain Personal Information

At your request, we will stop collecting, using, and/or disclosing Personal Information from or about your child in accordance with your request (for example, for just one activity or for all), but we reserve the right to keep certain information necessary for record-keeping to the extent permitted and/or required by law, including any statutory retention requirements.

To make these requests, you may contact our Customer Service at 800-246-2986 or at e-Scholastic, 557 Broadway, New York, NY 10012. Please indicate whether you are a parent or a teacher who has given consent on behalf of a school as the intermediary for a parent. Parents (not teachers) may also print, complete and return this letter to the specified address. Teachers may print, complete and return this letter to the specified address. Before processing your request, we may verify your identity and parent/guardian/teacher relationship with the child or student, or, if you are a teacher, that you have any required consent from the parent or through the school to act as an intermediary for these purposes.

**_"LINKED-TO" WEB SITES_**  
Our Kids Sites may contain links, banners or advertisements that lead to other third party Web sites or online services. We are not responsible for these other sites and services, and so the privacy policies on those sites (not this Policy) will govern the collection and use of information there. We encourage users to read the privacy policies of each Web site visited after leaving our Sites, and of each such third party service used, to learn about how their information is treated by others.

**_DATA PROCESSING IN THE UNITED STATES_**  
**Information provided to or collected by us on our Kids Sites is transmitted to us and processed in the United States and other countries, either by us or our service providers on our behalf, and will be protected subject to this Privacy Policy and applicable laws, which may not be as protective as the laws in other countries. Where permitted by applicable law, by allowing their children to use our Kids Sites, parents agree to the preceding sentence.**

**_INTERNET SAFETY_**  
We encourage parents and teachers to talk with their children and students about how to be safe online. Here are some resources to help you do that.

  * Ways to Take Charge of the Web  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/article/ten-ways-takecharge-web](http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/article/ten-ways-takecharge-web)
  * Internet Safety Commandments  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2012/05/internet-safety-commandments-summer](http://www.scholastic.com/teachers/top-teaching/2012/05/internet-safety-commandments-summer)
  * Keeping Kids Safe Online  
[ http://www.scholastic.com/parents/resources/article/your-child-technology/keeping-kids-safe-online ](http://www.scholastic.com/parents/resources/article/your-child-technology/keeping-kids-safe-online)
  * <http://www.commonsensemedia.org/>
  * <http://www.ikeepsafe.org/>

_What is our legal basis of processing?_

Certain countries require us to explain the legal reasons we collect, use and share a child's Personal Information. We rely on several reasons to collect, use and share your  Personal Information, including: (1) in order to provide our services to your child (so the games and activities your child would like to play); (2) in order to comply with the law (such as when we use your child's Personal Information for record keeping to satisfy legal and compliance obligations); (3) consent (where a parent has provided consent for their child, such as for marketing); and (4) necessary for business interests (such as when collect and use your child's data to maintain our business generally, which takes into account the impact on your child's privacy).

_How long do we retain your Personal Information?_

We typically retain Personal Information related to online activities for as long as you would like your child to continue to participate in such activities, and upon request, we will securely delete such data in accordance with applicable law.

**_CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICIES_**  
If we make a material change to our Kids Privacy Policy, we will make reasonable attempts to notify parents of child users by any means permitted by law, and we may require the parent's consent to any new privacy policy.

Parents may contact us with any questions concerning our policies or practices with regard to the collection, use and/or disclosure of their children's Personal Information:

Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 1-800-SCHOLASTIC  

If possible, when you contact us, please indicate the name of the Kids Site or other Site, division, product or service of Scholastic that you believe your child may have used or to which your question relates. A list of our Kids Sites and their operators is available here.

Effective Date: May 25, 2018

###  _ **Registration on Kids Sites**_

To register for an account on our Kids Sites, a child creates an anonymous user name through a combination of words selected from drop-down menus and an auto-generated random number. Kids also create a password. So that kids can get their password back if they forget it, we may ask users a security question when they register, or we may ask for the user's email address. If we ask for the user's email address, we send a one-time email to the user with the user's log-in credentials for his or her records. The email address is then hashed, which means it is changed so that we cannot read it, and used only to retrieve the user's account information at the user's request. Passwords and security questions do not ask for Personal Information. Registration on some of our Kids Sites may require country, state/province, gender and age information as part of registration, which we keep in the aggregate, not in the user's account or connected to any other information about the user. Of this information, only the anonymous user name may be publicly posted, but not in connection with any Personal Information unless we get parental consent. 

### _**Newsletters, Sweepstakes and Contests on Kids Sites**_

Kids can sign up for newsletters, sweepstakes and contests by submitting their email address along with an email address for their parent or guardian. This information is not combined with a child user's registration information (if any) and is not included in or displayed on a child user's public profile (if any).

For these activities, the child's email address is used only to respond more than once to that child's specific request in connection with a particular newsletter, sweepstakes or contest. The parent email address is collected to tell the parent that we have collected the child's email and why, and to give the parent the chance to let us know if he/she does not want the child to participate.

We provide information about how to unsubscribe in the newsletters we send.

For sweepstakes and contests, we also use the parent email to notify the parent if the child is selected as a potential winner and to coordinate fulfillment of the prize.

If a contest may allow child users to submit additional information about themselves (such as an essay contest), we will get consent from the child's parent before collecting that additional information, which we may do by email if the information will not be shared with third parties.

If a child is selected as a potential winner of a sweepstakes or contest, an offline affidavit or release must be signed by the parent and returned to us. This form may ask for additional Personal Information necessary to award the prize.

Unless a parent declines to let a child participate or asks us to delete a child's Personal Information, Personal Information collected from entrants or their parents in connection with a sweepstakes or contest entry will be retained in accordance with Scholastic's records retention policies, to the extent permitted and/or required by applicable law, including any statutory retention periods.

More details about Personal Information collected from kids in connection with a particular promotion may be set forth in the official rules for that sweepstakes or contest. 

### _**e-Cards on Kids Sites**_

Child users can also use e-cards, "email this", "invite a friend" or similar tools that let users share Kids Site content with others. These tools require the recipient's email address, and may require the sender's first name and last initial together with the first name and last initial of the recipient. The information submitted with the e-card is not combined with the sender's user name and password (if any), in our database or otherwise, and is not included in or displayed on any public profile the sender may have. Sender and recipient information is not kept after the e-card is sent, and child users cannot freely type a message to include with the e-card or in the subject line.

 **SCHOLASTIC KIDS SITES & OPERATORS LIST**

Site: | Operator(s):  
---|---  
Family Playground and other Kids Sites on Scholastic.com or distributed as mobile apps (unless otherwise specified in this list or in the privacy policy for a specific Kids Site or app) | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-SCHOLASTIC  
[Infinity Ring](http://infinityring.scholastic.com/privacy-policy) | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: help@infinityring.com or custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-724-6527 or 800-SCHOLASTIC  
[The 39 Clues](http://the39clues.scholastic.com/) | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-SCHOLASTIC  
[Spirit Animals](http://spiritanimals.scholastic.com/privacy-policy) | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-SCHOLASTIC  
Scholastic Summer Reading Challenge | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: summerchallenge@scholastic.com or custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-246-2986 or 800-SCHOLASTIC  
Read 100,000 | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012  
Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-SCHOLASTIC

READ 100,000 Program  
Scholastic Book Fairs Inc.  
1080 Greenwood Boulevard  
Lake Mary, FL 32746  
Email: read100khelp@scholasticbookfairs.com  
Phone: 800-874-4809 ext. 8269  
  
Scholastic Book Fairs App | Scholastic Inc.  
557 Broadway  
New York, NY 10012

Scholastic Book Fairs Inc.  
1080 Greenwood Boulevard  
Lake Mary, FL 32746

Email: custserv@scholastic.com  
Phone: 800-SCHOLASTIC
